Guide to the Operations and Maintenance Dept. Records, 1919 - 1957
Duke University. University Archives
Operations and Maintenance Dept. records 1919-1957
Duke University. Operations and Maintenance Dept
13.5 linear feet Extent: 12,000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
The Operations and Maintenance Department (and the organizations and individuals who preceded the establishment of the department) was responsible for construction and upkeep of Duke University Buildings. The Operations and Maintenance Department Records include correspondence, plans, architectural drawings, blueprints, financial records, contracts, desk diaries, keys, and other materials related to Duke buildings. Prominent individuals represented in the collection include Frank Clyde Brown, S.W. Myatt, and Horace Trumbauer. Major subjects include the building and administration of Duke University, the planning of buildings and grounds on the Duke Campus, and the establishment of the Duke Construction Company to oversee construction on campus. English.
UA.10.05.0001
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Provenance
The Operations and Maintenance Dept. Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1972 (A72-15, A72-16) and a gift in 1978 (A78-31).
Historical Note
The Operations and Maintenance Department, responsible for care of buildings and grounds, truly began in 1948, but several departments and groups carried out its functions prior to that date. The administration's Business Division had some responsibility for operations; the University Comptroller, Frank C. Brown, was in charge of some aspects of construction in the 1920s; and the Duke Construction Company, formed by the Duke Endowment, also held responsibility for construction. Please see the series scope and content notes for more information on the people and organizations responsible for operations and maintenance.
Collection Overview
The Operations and Maintenance Dept. Records include correspondence, plans, architectural drawings, blueprints, financial records, contracts, desk diaries, and other materials related to the construction, maintenance, and use of the buildings of Duke University. The bulk of the collection details the extensive planning and construction of Duke's new West Campus in the 1920s and 1940s, as well as renovations and additions to the East Campus. Discussions with vendors and suppliers, architectural plans and blueprints, and the design of the grounds all contribute to the record of Duke's growth. The collection also includes diaries kept by what became the Operations and Maintenance Department. These record campus events over a nearly twenty year period.
Subject Headings
Brown, Frank C. (Frank Clyde); Myatt, S. W. (Seth W.); Trumbauer, Horace, 1869-1938; Duke Construction Company; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Buildings; Duke University -- Buildings -- History -- 20th century; Duke University. Medical Center -- Buildings; Duke University. Operations and Maintenance Dept; Campus planning; Universities and colleges -- Planning; Architectural drawings; Blueprints; Building plans; Diaries; Keys (hardware); Site plans
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Frank C. Brown Files, 1919-1941
  Frank Clyde Brown was the supervisor of construction of the new buildings on the West Campus of Duke University from 1925-1930, as well as a literature professor at Duke. The files in this series pertain mainly to planning the construction of new buildings on the Duke Campus. The biographical note in for the Frank Clyde Brown Papers (located in the Duke University Archives) notes:
  "Between 1924 and 1930, Brown was deeply absorbed in the expansion of Trinity College into Duke University, serving as a member of the Building Committee of the Board of Trustees and as the first comptroller of the University. As comptroller, he acted as the liaison for architects, contractors, suppliers, administrators, and faculty in the designing, construction, and equipping of the redesigned East Campus, which became the Woman's College, and of the completely new West Campus. Brown is credited with contributing many original ideas to the building plans, foremost of which was the discovery of the nearby Hillsborough, N.C. stone and the recommendation that this material be utilized in the construction of the Gothic West Campus. He also served as university marshal, planning all major formal celebrations and entertaining numerous distinguished visitors to the new university."
  Brown's files in this series mainly contain correspondence, plans, contracts, some architectural drawings, and other materials related to construction. Several files have more relation to his interest in literature and his position as professor. Researchers should be aware that the materials in this series and the materials in the Frank Clyde Brown Papers are very closely related, and both collections may need to be examined.
  - Academic Costume, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alms Basin Design, [undated] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Academy of Arts & Letters - Committee for Good Diction on the Radio, 1929-1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Buildings, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes cost of Woman's College; contract with Trumbauer for West Campus; statement of general conditions for West Campus; and detail of reductions in original campus on West to reduce cost. Also includes 1 building plan.
  - Carolina Power & Light, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Celebration, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chapel - Collection Plates, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes 2 drawings.
  - Chicago, University of, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Class Ring, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Class Schedules and Room Assignments, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clement, E.H., 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Contracts, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cooperative Store, [undated] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Copyright, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cornerstone Laying, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Costs, 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Costs, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Costs of Education, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Davidson College, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Davison, Wilburt C., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dedication of Hospital
    - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Programs, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Dogwood Festival, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dormitories, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dormitory Plans, [undated] (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Includes 12 building plans.
  - Duke, B.N. and Family, 1923-1929 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Duke Construction Company, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Duke Endowment, 1925-1929 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Includes information on the Hillsborough Quarry; limestone and granite; library; and heating plant.
  - Duke Endowment - Local, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Duke Forest, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Duke, J.B., 1925 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Duke University Press, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Duke University Properties, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Duke's Chapel (includes specs), 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Durham Chamber of Commerce, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Durham Lumber Company, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Faculty, 1927-1938 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Faculty Apartments, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Few, William Preston, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Few, William Preston - 25th Anniversary as President, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Flowers, R.L., 1926-1937 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Fuller, George A., Co., 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Gross, Paul (regarding design of chemistry building), 1927-1934 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Hall, B.M, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Kittrell College, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Includes 1 site plan.
  - Literary Societies, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - London Hospital, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Long, Guy A. (steward), 1927 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Meredith College, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous, 1929-1939 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - North Carolina Central University, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - North Carolina Conservation and Development Department, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Noyes Scholarships, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Olmsted Brothers, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Petitions, [undated] (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Phi Delta Theta, 1925-1934 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Includes information on re-installation of the fraternity and the philosophy behind quads and fraternities in the architectural scheme of the university.
  - Portraits (locations), [undated] (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Property Rentals, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Publicity, circa 1920s (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Includes a mention of Met exhibition, detailed analysis of stone materials.
  - Red Cross, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Research Council, 1926-1939 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Salaries at other institutions, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Seals
    - Duke University, [undated] (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - North Carolina Counties, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - South Carolina Counties and North Carolina Towns, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Universities, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Seely Company, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Includes 1 blueprint, "Proposed Change in Boiler Room, B.N. Duke, Resident."
  - Smith, Winford H. (consultant from Johns Hopkins on the medical school and hospital), 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Soda Fountain, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Includes 3 building plans
  - Southern Power Company, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Includes negotiations on tunnel under Southern Railway East/West.
  - Southern Railway, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    Contract for spur track to heating plat on Campus Drive and for track to Hillsborough Quarry.
  - Student Discipline, 1926 [RESTRICTED: Contains student records] (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Subpoena, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Telephone Directory, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Trumbauer, Horace
    - 1926 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - February, 1927-January, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      Includes 1 blueprint drawing.
    - January, 1928-June, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - July, 1928-August, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - 1938 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Stonework Details, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - University of Michigan (letter discussing library critique), 1927-1929 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - University of Paris, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Vanderbilt University, 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Wesleyan College (Macon, GA), 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Wiley Gray Orations, 1926-1931 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Work Reports (E.H. Clement Co.), 1925-1927 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Work Reports (George A. Fuller Co.), 1927 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- S.W. Myatt Files, 1927-1957
  The S.W. Myatt Files series contains information about construction on the Duke Campus. Seth W. Myatt served as one of the Directors of the Duke Construction Company, as well as an Assistant to the President. The series contains correspondence, plans, contracts, many architectural drawings and blueprints, and other details related to construction at Duke in the 1930s, 1940s, and 1950s. A large post-war building program was undertaken at Duke from 1946 onward. During this period the growth of science and engineering projects jumped due to increased veteran enrollment in these programs. In addition to the materials mentioned above, the S.W. Myatt series also contains a collection of keys that were used in several Duke buildings.
  - Ackland Museum of Art (Proposed), circa 1938 (Box 3, Folder 88-89)
    Includes 22 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Aims of the University Plaque, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Air Conditioning for Colored Clinic, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Air Force ROTC Unit, 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Allen Building
    - Blueprints, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 93-94)
      Includes 18 architectural drawings and building plans.
    - Correspondence with Office of Horace Trumbauer, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Costs, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Daily Construction Report, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - National Production Authority, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Specifications, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Anderson St. Paving, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Apartment House for Pinecrest Road (Proposed), [undated] (Box 3, Folder 101)
    Includes 1 architectural drawing.
  - Aboretum Plans and Proposals, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    Includes 2 site plans.
  - Architecture of Duke - Addresses by W.P. Few, 1931, [undated] (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Asbury Building - Renovation Costs, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Aycock Hall Alterations, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    Includes 4 building plans.
  - Baseball Stadium - Proposed Bleacher Seats Addition, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Bivens Hall Alterations & Art Building Alterations (formerly Aeronautical Bldg.), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    Includes 5 building plans.
  - Branson Building Alterations, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 108-109)
    Includes 1 building plan.
  - Bus Operation, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Cabins for Interns and Medical Students, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Camp Butner Dormitories Assigned to Duke, circa 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    Includes 2 building plans.
  - Camp Butner Veterans Housing, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Cathedral Terrace Apartments, 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Chapel
    - Acoustics Inquiry, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Altar Cloths, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Altar Frontals - Blueprints, 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 117)
      Includes 1 drawing.
    - Article, circa 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Reredos and Cross Additions, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      Includes 4 architectural drawings.
    - Sarcophagi, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Windows - Plans and Costs, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Chapel Road Paving, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Construction Projects
    - Building Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Correspondence with Office of Horace Trumbauer, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Estimated Costs, 1946-1951 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Estimated Costs, 1952-1956 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - General Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Crowell Building - Renovation Costs, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Drama and Dramatic Arts Building - Proposed (old war building to move), 1947 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    Includes 3 building plans.
  - Duke Centennial Fund, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Duke Memorial Methodist Church, 1936-1940 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Duke Memorial Methodist Church - Blueprints for Chapel, [undated] (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Duke Power Company - Transmission Map, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Duke University Golf Course - Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Duke University Properties in High Point & Greensboro, NC, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Duke University Roads & Utilities, 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Durham-Chapel Hill Boulevard (Bus. 15-501), 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Durham - Extension of City Limits to include West Campus, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Durham Roads & Thoroughfares, 1936-1946 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    Includes 3 maps.
  - Durham Water Meters, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - East Campus Dormitories - Floor Plans, [undated] (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - East Campus Garages, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - East Campus Map - Existing, Proposed, and Future Buildings, [undated] (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - East Campus Plot Plan, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Engineering and Surveying Equipment, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Engineering Buildings - East Campus (proposed), [undated] (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Epworth Inn Alterations, 1949-1951 (Box 4, Folder 147-148)
    Includes 5 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Erwin Road, 1934, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Erwin Road Re-location, 1946-1953 (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Faculty Apartments - East Campus (Proposed), [undated] (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Faculty Club & Guest House (Proposed), [undated] (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Faculty House No. 2 - Proposed Alterations (to make into 2 apartments), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Faculty Houses on Campus Drive, 1933-1938 (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Few Quadrangle Floor Plans, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Flowers Residence (Dr. Robert L.)
    - Blueprints and Specifications, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 156)
      Includes 4 architectural drawings and building plans.
    - Costs, 1931-1936 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Interior Decoration, 1931-1935 (Box 4, Folder 158-159)
  - Forestry Building, School of (Proposed), 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    Includes 1 site plan, and 8 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Garden Projects for the Unemployed, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Gate at Entrance Circle - West Campus (Proposed), 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Gilbert-Addoms Residence Hall - Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Government Surplus Property - Justification of Need and Supplements, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Government Surplus Property - Medical School, Engineering, Physics, Forestry, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Grants-in-Aid Program Correspondence, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Hanes-Flowers House Exchange Agreement, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Hanes House, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Hanes House Annex (originally the Auxiliary Nurses Home), 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    Includes 2 site plans and 1 architectural drawing.
  - Hanes House - Blueprints, 1940-1950 (Box 4, Folder 170-172)
    Includes 23 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Hanes Residence (Dr. Frederic M.), 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Hanes Residence (Dr. Frederic M.), 1936 (Folder 174, Box 5)
  - Hart House (Dr. Daryl), 1933-1935 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Heating Plant - West Campus, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 176)
    Includes 1 architectural drawing and 1 site plan.
  - Hillsborough Quarry, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Hospital Addition - Financial Statements, 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Hospital Diagnostic & Treatment Center - Financial Statements, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Hospital Laundry, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Hospital, Medical School, and Nurses Home - Alterations and Additions, 1931, 1940-1946 (Box 5, Folder 181-182)
    Includes 22 architectural drawings, site plans, and building plans.
  - Hospital Refrigeration Room
    - Architect: Office of Horace Trumbauer, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 183)
    - Blueprints, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 184)
      Includes 8 architectural drawings and building plans.
    - Contractors, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - Specifications, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - War Production Board, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Hospital Service Building
    - Architect: Office of Horace Trumbauer, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 188)
    - Blueprints, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 189)
    - Contractors, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Financial Statements, 1946-1950 (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Specifications, circa 1946 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Hudson Hall - College of Engineering
    - 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - Blueprints, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 194-195)
      Includes 10 architectural drawings and building plans.
    - Payroll Forms (Sampled) - RESTRICTED, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Indoor Stadium (Proposed), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    Includes 3 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Institutional Salaries, [undated] (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Insurance Valuation Report, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    Includes 2 site plans and lists of square footages.
  - Jarvis Hall Addition and Alteration, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Kilgo Quadrangle Floor Plans, [undated] (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Kittrell College, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Law School (Proposed, in location of present Allen Building), [undated] (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Libraries - Proposed Additions, circa 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    Includes 2 architectural drawings and building plans.
  - Log Cabins for Law Students, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Marine Laboratory - Property Plat, 1935, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    Includes 1 property plat.
  - Medical Research Building, 1945-1949 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Medical Research Building Addition No. 1, 1947-1951 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    Includes 1 building plan and 1 site plan.
  - Medical Research Building Addition No. 2 (cancer and heart research building), 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 209-210)
  - Medical School Alterations, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1950-1966 (Box 6, Folder 318)
  - National Housing Act, [undated] (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - National Housing Advisory Committee of the American Council on Education, 1946-1948 (Box 6, Folder 213)
    Myatt was a member of the committee
  - Navy Building (Proposed), 1945 (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - North Carolina Colored Orphanage, 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Northwestern University, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Olmsted Brothers, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Olmsted Brothers - Planting Plan for West Campus, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Orange County, NC, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 219)
  - Outpatients Clinic and Private Patients Clinic Building - Financial Statements, 1946-1957 (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Page Auditorium Alterations - Contractors, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - Page Auditorium Alterations - Financial Statements, 1953-1955 (Box 6, Folder 222)
  - Pan-Hellenic Building (Proposed), 1935 (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - Parking, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 224)
    Includes 9 building plans.
  - Paving and Drainage South of Indoor Stadium (Proposed), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - Pegram Dormitory - Proposed Additions, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - Perkins Library
    - Addition, 1945-1952 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - Addition - Blueprints and Specifications, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 228-230)
      Includes 19 architectural drawings and building plans.
    - Rare Book Room Interior Decoration, 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Physics Building
    - 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 232)
    - Blueprints and Specifications, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 233-234)
      Includes 9 architectural drawings and building plans.
    - Addition (Van de Graaff Accelerator Wing), 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - Addition (Van de Graaff Accelerator Wing) - Blueprints and Specifications, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Plot Plan for Duke University, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Prefabricated Houses, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    Includes 2 building and site plans.
  - Preliminary Building Expense - Faculty Ledger, 1945-1947 (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - President's House Furniture Inventory (Mrs. W.P. Few), 1933, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Private Diagnostic Clinic Air Conditioning 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Private Patients Building Vestibule, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Proposed Buildings and Expansion Plans, 1936-1949 (Box 7, Folder 243)
    Includes 12 architectural drawings, site plans, and building plans.
  - Psychiatric Clinical Training Building
    - Blueprints, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 244)
    - Correspondence with War Assets Administration, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - Financial Statements, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 246)
    - Specifications, circa 1946 (Box 7, Folder 247)
  - Quadrangle Design - Elevation Drawings, [undated] (Box 7, Folder 248)
  - Railroad Equipment Sale, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 249)
  - Rental Houses on Erwin Road and Adjoining Streets, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 250)
  - Rental Properties, 1933-1936 (Box 7, Folder 251)
  - Sarah P. Duke Gardens, 1936, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 252)
  - Sarah P. Duke Gardens - Drainage Area, 1934-1937 (Box 7, Folder 253)